what's up everybody Phil Blackman with
barbend.com we just finished up the
penultimate day at the 2023 CrossFit
Games in Madison Wisconsin three more
events shook up the leaderboard for the
individual competition heading into the
final day where it is extremely likely
that we are going to say I knew fittest
man on Earth crowd and a guarantee that
we're gonna see a new fittest woman on
earth ground if you want to follow along
with any of the barban coverage of the
CrossFit Games thus far or going into
the final day or any strength sport in
general whether it be strong man
powerlifting weightlifting bodybuilding
or of course CrossFit hit that subscribe
button so you don't miss out on any of
the coverage the third day of
competition for the individual athletes
at the 2023 CrossFit Games in Madison
Wisconsin began with Emma Lawson and
Roman coronaco Atop The leaderboards the
women's division was a tight race at the
top Lawson had a narrow lead over Alexis
raptis and Laura Horvath with two days
of competition left to go however the
story on the men's side was completely
different Roman chronicov had built
himself a gigantic lead and would only
need to play defense for the rest of the
weekend in order to be Crown the fittest
man on Earth if any of the men were
going to make a dent into that lead they
would have to do so starting with a
cross-country 5K which kicked off the
penultimate day at the games the task
was simple each athlete simply had to
run 5K in the fastest possible time on
the women's side what are we even
talking about Emily Rolfe what a
performance she gets out to an early
lead and never gives it up she's the
only female athlete to cross the finish
line in a sub 18 minute time to attack
100 points onto her total Alexis Raptors
came in fourth place which was
significant because it was three ranks
ahead of the overall leader Emma Lawson
who finished in seventh Laura Horvath
finished in 13th and would need to make
up the Gap in the later events which
have played to her strength on the men's
side Roman karenikov set the early Pace
but he couldn't hold it Jeffrey Adler
yellow hosted Lazar dusick they were the
ones who were able to maintain the
steady leading Pace all the way through
until the end it seemed that Jeffrey
Adler was going to make a hundred points
onto his total and chip into Roman
krenikov's lead but yellow hosta at the
final second he turned on the Jets he
crosses the Finish Line first in the
fastest time of any athlete in the field
at 16 39.68 five seconds later Adler
crosses the finish line Roman karenikov
not wanting to give up too much ground
to Adler he turned on the Jets and
sprinted across the Finish Line in a
time of 16 5708 Lazar 2 6 Brett fakowski
Jay Crouch and Chandler Smith alongside
oldest supanics and will Morad were able
to get in as vellner was absolutely
gassed out by the end and velner
finishes in 10th while it's not a lot
Adler did make a three-point Dent into
Roman chronicov's lead heading into the
second event of the day the eighth event
for the individuals would test their
heart rate Under Pressure titled
intervals each athlete had to perform
box jump overs rowing and Burpee box
jumpovers in a classic CrossFit 2159 rep
scheme that would perform two intervals
in the fastest time possible and then
rest until the six minute Mark where
they would then reverse course each
athlete's score was the total cumulative
time to complete all four intervals on
the women's side I mean it's not even
close Emma Lawson comes in wearing the
leader's Jersey she proves why she got
to wear the red and white down the
course she's the only female athlete to
finish in a sub 8-minute time she across
the Finish Line 7 48-64 she tacked 100
points onto her lead and McCary comes in
in a solid second place finish at
801-67. Alexis raptis entered the event
only seven points behind Lawson but she
gave up some ground as she finished in
12th overall at a time of 8 39-20
however Laura Horvath sitting in third
she bumped up the leaderboard a little
bit with an eighth place finish at 8
32.50 on the men's side and absolutely
dominant scorched Earth performance by
Patrick vellner he came out the gates
blazing he never gave up the lead he
comes across the Finish Line in first
place in a time of 7 21-36 to have the
fastest time in the field notably
Roman krenikov entered with the lead a
dominant lead but he finishes here in
17th Place at 8 2409 it's not because he
wasn't necessarily the fastest Athlete
on the floor but he had two catastrophic
blunders that cost him a ton of time the
first one you can see here he misses a
rep on the box jump over he's sort of
confused about where to go he has to
come back he has to finish his rep
before he can get back onto the rower it
cost him approximately two reps worth of
time that wasn't the end of it though
you can see here he runs past the box
jumps on the way to the rower gets on
the rower as his judges flagging him to
come back he doesn't recognize it
potentially a language barrier here that
cost him some time but it was
significant it dropped him multiple
ranks down the leaderboard it allowed
Jeffrey Adler who was coming into the
day in a Podium position to catch up
Jeffrey Adler finishes in seventh
overall at a time of 757-1-6 and Roman
chronicov finishes in 17th Place at 8
2409 the wheels are falling off for
Roman karenikov despite having his huge
lead he would not be able to afford
those kinds of blunders again going in
to the final event of the day which of
course is the Olympic total I mean what
would a game Saturday night be in
Madison if it didn't finish in the arena
with the athletes lifting immensely
heavy weights each athlete was tasked to
establish their one rep max snatch and
their one rep max clean and jerk their
score would be their cumulative total
load Emma Lawson wore the leaders jersey
for the women throughout the entirety of
day five and she would do so again here
in the final event of the day Ariel
lowen was right behind her on the
leaderboard 37 points back so Emma
Lawson did have some room to give Roman
krenikov still had a dominant lead on
the leaderboard however Jeffrey Adler
made a significant dent in that lead
over the first two events of this day
and he would go into his final event his
best event in the arena which is pretty
much any time that man has a barbell in
his hands it's unbelievable let's get
into how it shook out Laura Horvath on
the women's side 470 pound total she
takes 100 points and moves herself into
Podium contention and even nipping away
at Lawson on the overall leaderboard
potentially to score that fittest woman
on earth crown Christine coleenbrander
comes in second and Karen freyova also
posting into the 440s as did Amanda
Barnhart down in seventh place Emma
Lawson 433 pounds she didn't give up too
much ground on her way as she overtook
both Ariel lowen who finished that
fourth in 14th Place at 422 pounds and
notably Alexis wrapped us down in 22nd
Place who finished with 404 pounds on
the men's side it was the story of 21
year old Jack Farlow a dominant dominant
unbeatable dominant performance 701
pounds Jack Farlow is the only athlete
to eclipse the 700 pound Milestone he
set a 396 pound cleaning jerk which is
the heaviest single lift in CrossFit
Games history in the event an
unbelievable performance by Jack Farlow
he scores the top score of 701 pounds to
claim 100 points onto his name Jeffrey
Adler fourth place tied for fourth with
Mort's five big 642 pounds he makes
another dent into the lead of Roman
chronic off we've finished all the way
down in 17 8th Place at 617 pounds tied
with World morat notably Justin Medeiros
finished in 15th Place with 621 pounds
unfortunately for him he's had a rough
couple of early days to start the games
it is unlikely that he is going to be
able to mount a significant comeback to
defend his title we are likely going to
see a new fittest man on Earth crowned
at the end of the weekend Chandler Smith
finishes in 10th Place 628 pounds he's
also vying for a Podium spot Brent
fakowski still in the running for a
Podium position finishes tied for eighth
place overall in the event 629 pounds
with Dal and pepper Patrick velner as
well not out of it yet after missing a
couple of snatch attempts he finishes
with 623 pounds which is good enough for
12th Place tied with Bailey Martin
Goodman sin in this event there was
something noticeably wrong he only
loaded 95 pounds on his snatch and then
95 pounds on his cleaning jerk he never
made a second attempt when he didn't
have to he just wanted to secure himself
through the cut to the top 20 athletes
by posting a total however he finished
in last place there is no word yet as to
what injury he may may have sustained
but we're going to see how that impacts
his final day of competition at the
games in Madison as we head into the
final day there is only one event that
has been spoiled it's muscle up logs
it's comprised of muscle ups and heavy
sandbags over a trio of logs we're gonna
see if Emma Lawson can hold her lead
likewise with Roman karenikov so let's
take a look at the overall standings
heading into the final day on the men's
side Roman karenikov sits Atop The
leaderboard as expected with 716 points
however his lead is significantly less
than it was at the start of the weekend
Jeffrey Adler did an immense amount of
work to chip away at that lead he sits
in second place only 13 points behind
Roman a steep fall off down to Third
Place Chandler Smith sitting in the
bronze position with 628 points that's
16 points ahead of Patrick vellner and
uh Patrick fellner sits ahead of Brent
fakowski in fifth overall with 606
points that means that the likely
outcome of the 2023 CrossFit Games will
be a new fittest man on Earth that will
likely either be Roman kranikov or
Jeffrey Adler of note two-time defending
champion Korean Justin Maderos he sits
in 14th overall with 444 points so even
with a perfect run even a remotely
reasonable competition finish by Roman
krenikov and Jeffrey Adler will prevent
Justin Maderos from three pittings so
we're likely to see a new fittest man on
Earth either Roman chronicop or Jeffrey
Adler barring some crazy shenanigans
that are unforeseeable at this point on
the women's side Emma Lawson a dominant
performance so far she's been consistent
throughout the entire competition she's
the only woman to have 700 plus points
on the leaderboard she sits in the top
overall ahead of Laura Horvath in second
place with 681 points Ariel lowen of the
United States 668 points that puts her
on the podium if she can maintain it
she's got a significant lead over Alexis
raptis who sits in fourth overall at 626
points no other athlete in the field has
600 points yet except Gabriella magala
in fifth overall has 593 points so as we
head into the final day we're expecting
three workouts only one of which has
been spoiled thus far if Emma Lawson can
hold it down she will become the new
Finnish woman on earth the first time a
different Finnish woman on earth is
crowned other than Tia Claire Toomey in
seven years if Emma Lawson can do it it
would be an absolutely worthwhile
Victory given the performance that she's
had this weekend so far so there is a
lot of action heading into the final day
of the 2023 CrossFit Games it looked
like Roman krenikov was out to an early
lead that was going to be insurmountable
doing a little bit of flashback of
dominance in the Matt Frazier era but
Roman chronikov gave a lot of points
back to Jeffrey Adler and it looks like
a two-horse race for the men's title the
women's side it's still close it's
technically anybody's game but Emma
Lawson does have some room to give in
order to become the fittest woman on
earth so we at bar Ben will keep you up
to date on all of the coverage that
happens in the final day a lot of things
could happen a lot of unexpected game
changers are still in the mix there are
two events that are unknown going into
the final day so I am Phil Blackman from
barbara.com thank you for watching we
will keep you up to date on all of the
2023 CrossFit Games coverage until then
I am signing off thank you for watching
[Music]
thank you